Kseniia McFadden

Gardnerville, Nevada | 301-433-1692 | mcfaddenkseniia@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Blog

RUBY ON RAILS ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer with experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in customer service, banking, procurement, and logistics. Passionate about coding because it combines technique and creativity, provides challenge to constantly learn and be engaged in a high growth, fast paced environment. Diligent, organized, respectful team player, who can adapt, solve problems, and collaborate to meet and exceed team goals. I prioritize competing tasks, meet deadlines, and deliver a quality product.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, SQLite, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Get Together - GitHub | Demo | Deployed

This app is built with intention to help friends to get together and have a great time without hustle of messaging everyone separately.

- Built Rails API and React frontend that can be deployed to a single domain.
- Implemented Nested attributes, what allowed user to create new category, while creating new event.
- Used Polymorphic Active Record Associations to provide user with 2 roles 'Host' and 'Guest'.
- Created Context in React frontend to share logged in user information throughout the app.
- Incorporated Material UI library for styling components

Project Tracker - GitHub | Demo | Deployed

Purpose of this app is help user to keep track of clients, employees, and projects they work on.

- Built Rails API and React frontend that can be deployed to a single domain.
- Implemented password protection, authentication, and authorization for users using 'bcrypt' gem and cookies
- Created 5 models on the backend, that include one-to-many and many-to-many relationship

Bucket List - GitHub | Demo

Helper application for users to keep track of their bucket lists.

- Built Sinatra API backend that uses Active Record to access and persist data in a database.
- Built a separate React frontend application that interacts with the API to perform CRUD actions.
- Created two models with a one-to-many relationship, with full CRUD capability for one of them.

EXPERIENCE

Lead associate of operations, JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Gardnerville, Nevada 10/2018 - 11/2021

- Supervised employees to ensure financial transactions were completed accurately and efficiently, while complying
 with all policies and regulatory banking requirements, as a result passing all audit reviews and appearing on top of
 monthly operations reports.
- Solved issues to client's satisfaction effectively and efficiently, utilizing strong knowledge of proper procedures and positive client engagement.
- Mentored junior team members resulting strong performance, trusting and respectful relationship.

Procurement Specialist, Rosneft

Irkutsk, Russian Federation 08/2015 – 04/2017

- Collaborated with internal and external parties to affect satisfactory and timely solutions to diverse issues and improve the efficiency of receiving supplies.
- Determined project schedules and gm generated reports, maintained timeline with proactive adjustments to workflow, detailing project information and predictions.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, Certificate Flatiron School

Gardnerville, Nevada 11/2021 -08/2022

Bachelor's degree, Crisis Management

Irkutsk State Railway University

Irkutsk, Russia 06/ 2010